Say we want to get a sense of how our returns are going to vary in the future.
假设我们想知道收益率在未来会如何变化
That is to say, we want to estimate the volatility of a stock we've invested in.
即我们想估算所投资股票的波动率
How do we do it? Well, the simplest way is to calculate
如何估算？最简单的方法是
the standard deviation of the log returns of some price data that we have for this stock,
计算该股票的股价数据对数收益率的标准差
eg data from the past.
例如过去的数据
This is called historical volatility.
称为历史波动率
The first step is to calculate log returns from prices.
第一步是计算股价的对数收益率
The first log return datum will be undefined
第一个对数收益率不确定
since there is no price datum from the time point proceeding it.
因为它之前的股价数据不存在
So, if you start with n plus one price data,
如果以 n+1 的股价数据开始
you will now have n log returns.
将有 n 的对数收益率
Then, the formula for volatility is the formula for standard deviation,
波动率的公式就是标准差公式
where the observations are log returns.
观察量是对数收益率
One thing to keep in mind is that,
需要注意的一点是
since volatility is defined as the standard deviation,
因为波动率是用标准差定义的
it treats log returns that are above and below the mean the same way.
所以它不区分高于和低于均值的对数收益率
This is because in the calculation of standard deviation,
这是因为 在计算标准差时
price differences relative to the mean are squared,
价格相对于均值的差异会求平方
so that negative and positive differences are combined into one quantity.
所以负差异和正差异没有区别
So, after doing these calculations for this small dataset,
对这个小数据集进行计算后
we'd get sigma equals 0.025.
得出 σ=0.025
Since our dataset consisted of daily prices,
因为数据集由每日价格组成
this is the estimate of the daily volatility.
所以这是每日波动率的估算值
Sometimes though, instead of having a price for every day,
但有时候 我们可能没有每天的价格
you might only have a price for every week,
只有每星期的价格
or a price for every month.
或每月的价格
If you take these data,
如果用这些数据
calculate the log returns,
计算对数收益率
and then calculate the standard deviation,
然后计算标准差
you would get a different number for the volatility.
可能会获得不同的波动率值
For example, for stocks,
例如 对于股票来说
the standard deviation of daily log returns is typically around 0.006 to 0.03,
每日对数收益率的标准差通常约为 0.006 - 0.03
while the standard deviation of weekly log returns is typically around 0.01 to 0.07.
而每周对数收益率的标准差通常约为 0.01 - 0.07
If you think about it, this makes sense.
思考下 会发现这很合理
This is just telling you that stock prices change
表明股价在一周内的变化
more over the course of a week than over the course of a day.
比在一天内的变化要大
So weekly returns vary more widely than daily returns.
所以每周收益率比每日收益率变化更大
So your volatility estimate depends on the time frequency of the underlying price data.
波动率估算值取决于底层股价数据的时间频率
But we want to be able to come up with
但是我们希望获得一个
a volatility number that we can compare across different situations and datasets.
能够比较不同情形和数据集的波动率值
In order to do this,
为了进行这种比较
people typically calculate a value that
人们通常计算
corresponds to the standard deviation of annual log returns.
年度对数收益率的标准差的估计值
If you don't have several years of data,
如果你没有多年的数据
and you can't calculate the standard deviation of annual log returns,
并且不能计算年度对数收益率的标准差
you can calculate the standard deviation of log returns of
那么可以计算另一个频率的对数收益率标准差
another frequency and extrapolate it to an annual one.
并外推成年度标准差
This is called calculating the annualized volatility.
称为年化波动率
And we're going to talk about it in the next lesson.
我们将在下节课介绍